<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks on Cr0w&#39;s Place</title>
    <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/tags/talks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks on Cr0w&#39;s Place</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Thomas Sermpinis</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 16:56:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cr0wtom.github.io/tags/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - How I Hacked My Way to the Security Sector {And why you should always do what you love, no matter what people say!}</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-storytellers24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-storytellers24/</guid>
      <description>It all started 30 years ago… hm, that’s a bit too much, let me try again.
It all started 18 years ago, when I found a book of C in my uncles’ library. How stupid can you be to read C at 12 years old you might ask? A lot, but this is what brought me here.
A story of pain, passion, blood, sweat and tears, which aims to help people stop carrying about what other people say, follow their passion, and do everything in their hands to achieve their goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - V2GEvil: Ghost in the wires</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-v2gevil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-v2gevil/</guid>
      <description>This research is dedicated to enhancing the cybersecurity of electric vehicles, with a specific focus on identifying vulnerabilities in the Electric Vehicle Communication Controller (EVCC). This controller facilitates communication with the Supply Equipment Communication Controller during the charging process. Accessible through the On-Board Charging (OBC) port, which is as publicly available as the gas tank in combustion engine vehicles.
The research journey began by studying the electric vehicle charging ports, how they communicate, and the standards they follow, especially focusing on ISO 15118.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Back to the Future: Old Vulnerabilities Becoming New Again</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-back-to-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-back-to-the-future/</guid>
      <description>While hardware security is a topic of interest for decades, devices are constantly getting smaller, more powerful and more complicated. Most would assume that this resulted in higher security standards, but from our 100+ penetration tests in the (heavily hardware based) automotive industry, we beg to differ.
With automotive suppliers trying to make everything work under heavily constrained environments, with limited resources both for energy and processing power, understandably many things are getting left out of the table, with one of the biggest victim being security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Need For Speed: The Fight of Ownership</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-need-for-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-need-for-speed/</guid>
      <description>While the automotive industry starts to realize the mistakes of the past, penetration testers, researchers and automakers strive to create impenetrable vehicle components, with the ultimate purpose being safer streets inside and outside of our vehicles. However, as desirable as this can be, it had an impact in other aspects of the automotive landscape, notably in terms of privacy and ownership, out of many.
Tuners and car enthusiasts, while they might have no direct connection to cyber security, they have significantly contributed to vehicle vulnerabilities and exploitation over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - ASRG Prague Group</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-asrg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-asrg/</guid>
      <description> As the main contact of the ASRG Prague Group, I will be presenting a series of events, focused on Automotive Security. List to be updated with more information, as the events happen.
Event 1: ASRG Prague Meetup: Vehicle (In)Securities - Part 1
Event Link LinkedIn Link </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Horror Stories from the Automotive Industry</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-horror-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-horror-stories/</guid>
      <description>In this talk, we will revisit some of the scariest stories we faced during more than 50 penetration testing and security research projects, with a twist. In the ever-emerging industry of automotive, with old and new OEMs trying to get a share of the pie, many things are at stake, with many things getting overlooked, forgotten, or even deliberately covered. We will go through a journey of critical findings in different targets and the constant battle between penetration testers, developers, and mid to upper management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - UDS Fuzzing and the Path to Game Over</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-uds-fuzzing-troopers22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-uds-fuzzing-troopers22/</guid>
      <description>The automotive industry presented significant advances in the sector in the last decade, to catch up with the technological advances of the world. Lack of proper regulations and security standards meant that automotive companies had to develop custom solutions most of the time, which resulted in a lot of security issues. Security testing also fell behind, as there was no significant need till now to test and research those devices, but with more and more connected components the risks are increasing rapidly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Consensus Algorithms (Greek)</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-consensus-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-consensus-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Presentation at the &amp;ldquo;Bitcoin &amp;amp; Blockchain Tech Meetup (Thessaloniki)&amp;rdquo; taking place at Thessaloniki.
Presentation Video
Meetup Link
Slides</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research - Traceability Decentralization in Supply Chain Management Using Blockchain Technologies</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-traceability-decentralization-in-supply-chain-management-using-blockchain-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-traceability-decentralization-in-supply-chain-management-using-blockchain-technologies/</guid>
      <description>Conference talk and paper proceeding in the 4th Olympus International Conference on Supply Chains (14-15 September 2018, Katerini), on the topic &amp;ldquo;Traceability Decentralization in Supply Chain Management Using Blockchain Technologies&amp;rdquo;. Co-author Christos Sermpinis.
Abstract With the increase of web users and applications with real time requests, the ability to identify, track and trace elements of a product as it moves in the supply chain is deemed necessary, and for many industries is even mandated by national or international regulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Introduction to Bitcoin and Blockchain Technologies (Greek)</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-introduction-to-bitcoin-and-blockchain-technologies-greek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-introduction-to-bitcoin-and-blockchain-technologies-greek/</guid>
      <description>Presentation at the &amp;ldquo;Bitcoin and Machine Learning joint meetup&amp;rdquo; taking place at Thessaloniki.
Presentation Video
Slides
Meetup Link
Blog Post</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Integration of Augmented Reality technology into Warehouse Management Systems</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-integration-of-augmented-reality-technology-into-warehouse-management-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-integration-of-augmented-reality-technology-into-warehouse-management-systems/</guid>
      <description>Conference talk in the &amp;ldquo;12th Student Conference on Management Science and Technology&amp;rdquo; taking place in Athens on 14th of May 2015. The subject is my innovative idea on the &amp;ldquo;Integration of Augmented Reality technology into Warehouse Management Systems&amp;rdquo; based on my paper made in the context of my studies in the Technological Educational Institute of Central Macedonia.
Conference Link
Slides</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Integration of Near Field Communication technology into Warehouse Management Systems</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-integration-of-near-field-communication-technology-into-warehouse-management-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-integration-of-near-field-communication-technology-into-warehouse-management-systems/</guid>
      <description>Conference talk in the &amp;ldquo;12th Student Conference on Management Science and Technology&amp;rdquo; taking place in Athens on 14th of May 2015. The subject is my innovative idea on the &amp;ldquo;Integration of Near Field Communication technology into Warehouse Management Systems&amp;rdquo; based on my paper made in the context of my studies in the Technological Educational Institute of Central Macedonia.
Conference Link
Slides</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Penetration Testing with Android Devices</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-penetration-testing-with-android-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-penetration-testing-with-android-devices/</guid>
      <description>One of my first talks in the security industry happened in the Google DevFest 2014 Season of Thessaloniki. A brief visit to the ways of performing penetration testing with an Android device was presented.
Conference Link
Slides
Presentation Video</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
