<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Troopers24 on Cr0w&#39;s Place</title>
    <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/tags/troopers24/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Troopers24 on Cr0w&#39;s Place</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Thomas Sermpinis</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:56:46 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cr0wtom.github.io/tags/troopers24/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - How I Hacked My Way to the Security Sector</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks---storytellers24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks---storytellers24/</guid>
      <description>Title: How I Hacked My Way to the Security Sector {And why you should always do what you love, no matter what people say!}&#xA;Abstract:&#xA;It all started 30 years ago… hm, that’s a bit too much, let me try again.&#xA;It all started 18 years ago, when I found a book of C in my uncles’ library. How stupid can you be to read C at 12 years old you might ask?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - V2GEvil: Ghost in the wires</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks---v2gevil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks---v2gevil/</guid>
      <description>This research is dedicated to enhancing the cybersecurity of electric vehicles, with a specific focus on identifying vulnerabilities in the Electric Vehicle Communication Controller (EVCC). This controller facilitates communication with the Supply Equipment Communication Controller during the charging process. Accessible through the On-Board Charging (OBC) port, which is as publicly available as the gas tank in combustion engine vehicles.&#xA;The research journey began by studying the electric vehicle charging ports, how they communicate, and the standards they follow, especially focusing on ISO 15118.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
