<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Cr0w&#39;s Place</title>
    <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Cr0w&#39;s Place</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Thomas Sermpinis</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 16:56:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cr0wtom.github.io/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Chaos Computer Camp - Horror Stories from the Automotive Industry</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-horror-stories-ccc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-horror-stories-ccc/</guid>
      <description>In this talk, we will revisit some of the scariest stories we faced during more than 50 penetration testing and security research projects, with a twist. In the ever-emerging industry of automotive, with old and new OEMs trying to get a share of the pie, many things are at stake, with many things getting overlooked, forgotten, or even deliberately covered. We will go through a journey of critical findings in different targets and the constant battle between penetration testers, developers, and mid to upper management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - TROOPERS23 - Horror Stories from the Automotive Industry</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-horror-stories-troopers23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-horror-stories-troopers23/</guid>
      <description>In this talk, we will revisit some of the scariest stories we faced during more than 50 penetration testing and security research projects, with a twist. In the ever-emerging industry of automotive, with old and new OEMs trying to get a share of the pie, many things are at stake, with many things getting overlooked, forgotten, or even deliberately covered. We will go through a journey of critical findings in different targets and the constant battle between penetration testers, developers, and mid to upper management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - UDS Fuzzing and the Path to Game Over</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-uds-fuzzing-troopers22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-uds-fuzzing-troopers22/</guid>
      <description>The automotive industry presented significant advances in the sector in the last decade, to catch up with the technological advances of the world. Lack of proper regulations and security standards meant that automotive companies had to develop custom solutions most of the time, which resulted in a lot of security issues. Security testing also fell behind, as there was no significant need till now to test and research those devices, but with more and more connected components the risks are increasing rapidly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research - [CVE-2021-29507] Improper Input Validation leads to buffer overflow in dlt-daemon (0day)</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-dlt-daemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 12:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-dlt-daemon/</guid>
      <description>Title: Improper Input Validation leads to buffer overflow in dlt-daemon
Date: 12/05/2021
CVE-ID: CVE-2021-29507
Author: Thomas Sermpinis
Versions: 2.10.0 &amp;lt; version &amp;lt;= 2.18.6
Package URL: https://github.com/GENIVI/dlt-daemon/
Tested on: dlt-daemon 2.18.6
The dlt-daemon includes a configuration file load functionality (-c) which is vulnerable to a buffer overflow vulnerability and allows a malicious user to supply a specially crafted configuration file which results in a segmentation fault after improper validation of the file content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research - [CVE-2020-26800] Stack based buffer overflow while parsing JSON file in Aleth C&#43;&#43; Ethereum client (0day)</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-aleth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 12:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-aleth/</guid>
      <description>Title: Stack based buffer overflow while parsing JSON file in Aleth C++ Ethereum client
Date: 11/01/2021
CVE-ID: CVE-2020-26800
Author: Thomas Sermpinis
Versions: &amp;lt;= 1.8.0
Package URL: https://github.com/ethereum/aleth
Tested on: Aleth C++ Ethereum Client 1.8.0
An attacker can supply a specially crafted config.json file, consisting of 3764 left square brackets or more, which results in segmentation fault by the application. This immediately results in Denial of Service, and with more advanced exploitation it can have further implications, with higher severity security issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research - [CVE-2020-24807] File Type Restriction Bypass in Socket.io-file NPM module (0day)</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-socketio_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-socketio_2/</guid>
      <description>Title: File Type Restriction Bypass in Socket.io-file NPM module
Date: 31/07/2020
CVE-ID: CVE-2020-24807
Author: Thomas Sermpinis
Versions: &amp;lt;= 2.0.31
Package URL: -
Tested on: node v10.19.0, Socket.io-file v2.0.31, socket.io v2.3.0
All versions of socket.io-file are vulnerable to a file restriction bypass. The validation for valid file types only happens on the client-side, which allows an attacker to intercept the Websocket request post-validation and alter the name value to upload any file types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research - DeTRACT a decentralized, transparent, immutable and open PKI certificate framework</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-detract-a-decentralized-transparent-immutable-and-open-pki-certificate-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-detract-a-decentralized-transparent-immutable-and-open-pki-certificate-framework/</guid>
      <description>The academic paper based on my masters thesis and research made during my work with the OSwinds research team of the Aristotle Unicersity of Thessaloniki got published in Springers&amp;rsquo; Internationa Journal of Information Security by the name &amp;ldquo;DeTRACT a decentralized, transparent, immutable and open PKI certificate framework&amp;rdquo;.
Thanks to the team, George Vlahavas, Konstantinos Karasavvas &amp;amp; Athena Vakali.
Abstract Public key infrastructure (PKI) is widely used over the Internet to secure and to encrypt communication among parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research - [CVE-2020-15779] Path Traversal in Socket.io-file NPM module Functionality (0day)</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-socketio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-socketio/</guid>
      <description>Title: Path Traversal in Socket.io-file NPM module
Date: 18/05/2020
CVE-ID: 2020-15779
Author: Thomas Sermpinis
Versions: &amp;lt;= 2.0.31
Package URL: https://www.npmjs.com/package/socket.io-file
Tested on: node v10.19.0, Socket.io-file v2.0.31, socket.io v2.3.0
All versions of socket.io-file are vulnerable to Path Traversal. The package fails to sanitize user input and uses it to generate the file upload paths. The socket.io-file::createFile message contains a name option that is passed directly to path.join(). It is possible to upload files to arbitrary folders on the server by sending relative paths on the name value, such as .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Consensus Algorithms (Greek)</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-consensus-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-consensus-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Presentation at the &amp;ldquo;Bitcoin &amp;amp; Blockchain Tech Meetup (Thessaloniki)&amp;rdquo; taking place at Thessaloniki.
Presentation Video
Meetup Link
Slides</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research - Traceability Decentralization in Supply Chain Management Using Blockchain Technologies</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-traceability-decentralization-in-supply-chain-management-using-blockchain-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-traceability-decentralization-in-supply-chain-management-using-blockchain-technologies/</guid>
      <description>Presentation and paper proceeding in the 4th Olympus International Conference on Supply Chains (14-15 September 2018, Katerini), on the topic &amp;ldquo;Traceability Decentralization in Supply Chain Management Using Blockchain Technologies&amp;rdquo;. Co-author Christos Sermpinis.
Abstract With the increase of web users and applications with real time requests, the ability to identify, track and trace elements of a product as it moves in the supply chain is deemed necessary, and for many industries is even mandated by national or international regulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research - PKI Decentralization Using Blockchain Technologies</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-pki-decentralization-using-blockchain-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-pki-decentralization-using-blockchain-technologies/</guid>
      <description>My masters thesis, supervised by Athena Vakali, was based on blockchain technologies with the title “PKI Decentralization Using Blockchain Technologies”.
Abstract The Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) is used widely on the Internet in order to certify the identity of users, and as a result encrypt the communication between two parties and make it more secure. From this model, multiple problems can arise, most of them due to its centralized nature. In the past, there have been cases of Certificate Authorities distributing rogue certificates that resulted in attacks, targeting users of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Introduction to Bitcoin and Blockchain Technologies (Greek)</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-introduction-to-bitcoin-and-blockchain-technologies-greek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-introduction-to-bitcoin-and-blockchain-technologies-greek/</guid>
      <description>Presentation at the &amp;ldquo;Bitcoin and Machine Learning joint meetup&amp;rdquo; taking place at Thessaloniki.
Presentation Video
Slides
Meetup Link
Blog Post</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research - Integration of Near Field Communication into Warehouse Management Systems (BSc Thesis)</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-integration-of-near-field-communication-into-warehouse-management-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-integration-of-near-field-communication-into-warehouse-management-systems/</guid>
      <description>My bachelors thesis, supervised by Dimitrios Folinas, was based on NFC and WMS technologies with the title “Integration of Near Field Communication into Warehouse Management Systems”.
Abstract (Greek) Στην παρούσα εργασία θα αναφερθούμε και θα εξετάσουμε μία καινοτόμο εφαρμογή που έχει να κάνει με την εφαρμογή της τεχνολογίας NFC, και παράλληλα της πολιτικής BYOD, στα συστήματα WMS. Τα κύρια σημεία που εξετάστηκαν είναι το αν υπάρχει ενδιαφέρον από τους εργαζομένους, όσο αναφορά την εφαρμογή ενός τέτοιου συστήματος στον χώρο εργασίας τους, και αν είναι δυνατή η ανάπτυξη ενός ολοκληρωμένου συστήματος με την προσθήκη των τεχνολογιών και πολιτικών που προτείνονται.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Integration of Augmented Reality technology into Warehouse Management Systems</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-integration-of-augmented-reality-technology-into-warehouse-management-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-integration-of-augmented-reality-technology-into-warehouse-management-systems/</guid>
      <description>Conference talk in the &amp;ldquo;12th Student Conference on Management Science and Technology&amp;rdquo; taking place in Athens on 14th of May 2015. The subject is my innovative idea on the &amp;ldquo;Integration of Augmented Reality technology into Warehouse Management Systems&amp;rdquo; based on my paper made in the context of my studies in the Technological Educational Institute of Central Macedonia.
Slides</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Integration of Near Field Communication technology into Warehouse Management Systems</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-integration-of-near-field-communication-technology-into-warehouse-management-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-integration-of-near-field-communication-technology-into-warehouse-management-systems/</guid>
      <description>Conference talk in the &amp;ldquo;12th Student Conference on Management Science and Technology&amp;rdquo; taking place in Athens on 14th of May 2015. The subject is my innovative idea on the &amp;ldquo;Integration of Near Field Communication technology into Warehouse Management Systems&amp;rdquo; based on my paper made in the context of my studies in the Technological Educational Institute of Central Macedonia.
Slides</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research/Talks - Penetration Testing with Android Devices</title>
      <link>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-penetration-testing-with-android-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 16:56:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cr0wtom.github.io/projects/research-talks-penetration-testing-with-android-devices/</guid>
      <description>One of my first talks in the security industry happened in the Google DevFest 2014 Season of Thessaloniki. A brief visit to the ways of performing penetration testing with an Android device was presented.
Slides</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
